uniblue.com 2019-06-29

# Uniblue - Privacy Policy

Last Updated on 24th May 2018 | Version 24.05.2018

## INTRODUCTION

This Master Privacy Policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) relates to the website [http://www.uniblue.com](http://www.uniblue.com/) and/or any sub-website and/or associated domains (and/or sub-domains) of [http://www.uniblue.com](http://www.uniblue.com/) (hereinafter referred to as the “ **Site** ”) the services (which may include sale of goods if applicable) provided by **Uniblue Systems Limited** , the owner of the Site, (" **We**" , “ **Us** ”, “ **Our** ”, “ **Ourselves** ” and/or “ **Uniblue Systems Limited”** ) and any related software applications (‘Apps’), where Personal Data is processed by the same (via the Site, any of Our Apps or otherwise) relating to You. In this Master Privacy Policy, “ **You** ” and “ **Your** ” and “ **User** ” refer to an identified or identifiable natural person being the User of the Site and/or client (or prospective client) of any of Our services. Our full details, including contact details, can be read below.

**You may be reading this Privacy Policy as a User or visitor of the Site or You may have been directed here by one (or more) of Our condensed privacy policies, agreements or Our other notices (digital or otherwise).**

Although this Privacy Policy provides detailed, layered inforhttp://www.uniblue.com/privacy/mation on hhttp://www.uniblue.com/privacy/ow and why We _generally_ process Personal Data (via the Site, any of Our Apps, or otherwise) as well as detailed information about Your various rights, the specific and tailor-made content of such condensed policies or other notices will, in most cases, provide You with more focused and detailed information on _specific_ processing operations (for example, the specific legal basis for processing certain categories of Personal Data and the specific purpose for doing so depending on the matter at hand).

Although Our goal is to always be as clear and transparent as possible, We appreciate that legal documents can sometimes be difficult to read. However, We strongly encourage You to read this Privacy Policy (which is layered for Your convenience) with care. **Please do not hold back from contacting Us for any clarification You may need.** For example, if You need clarification on a specific legal basis We are relying on to process Your Personal Data for a specific processing operation, We would be happy to provide You with any such information You may need.http://www.uniblue.com/privacy/

## APPLICABLE LAWS

As an entity established in Malta, EU, the _main_ privacy laws that are applicable to Us in so far as You are concerned, are as follows:

  * The **Maltese Data Protection Act** (Chapter 586 of the Laws of Malta) as well as the various subsidiary legislation issued under the same – the ‘ **DPA** ’;
  * The **Regulation (EU) 2016/679** of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of Personal Data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC ( **General Data Protection Regulation** ) – the ‘ **GDPR** ’.

All the above referred to together as the **“Data Protection Laws.”**

## WHAT IS PERSONAL DATA?

“ **PERSONAL DATA** ” means any information that identifies You as an individual or that relates to an identifiable individual.

Whenever it is not possible or feasible for Us to make use of anonymous and/or anonymised data (in a manner that does not identify any Users of the Site or customers of Our services), We are nevertheless **committed to protecting Your privacy and the security of Your Personal Data at all times.**

We collect Personal Data in various ways, digitally via the Site (either when You choose to provide Us with certain data or in some cases, automatically or from third parties).

## PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

There are various **categories of Personal Data** that We collect about You, namely:

  * ### CONTACT DETAILS

  * ### MARKETING DATA

  * ### TRACKING DATA

  * ### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

## HOW AND WHY WE COLLECT PERSONAL DATA

As a general rule, We do not collect any Personal Data, that is, information that identifies You as an individual **other than that which You choose to provide to Us** such as the data (including Contact Details) You provide when registering with Our Site (where and if this is made available), when contacting Us with enquiries relating to Our goods and/or services, when subscribing to any service offered by Us or via Our Site, such as any newsletters as may be issued by Us from time to time or even when subscribing to any offers We (and/or Our affiliates and/or corporate partners) may offer from time to time (see Personal Data We Collect About You above).

Unless otherwise specified and subject to various controls, as a general rule, **We only collect Personal Data (from You or elsewhere) that We:**

  * **Need to be able to provide You with the goods and/or services You request from Us**
  * **Are legally required to collect/use and to keep for a predetermined period of time**
  * **Believe to be necessary for Our legitimate business interests**

For a detailed description of the reasons why we process specific categories of personal data as well as the corresponding legal ground(s) for doing so, please see **** the ‘What We Use Your Personal Data For (Purpose of Processing) below.

## PERSONAL DATA RELATING TO THIRD PARTIES

By providing Us with or allowing Us to access Personal Data relating to individuals other than Yourself, You are letting Us know that You have the authority to send Us that Personal Data or the authority to permit Us to access those data in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

## WHAT WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA FOR (PURPOSE OF PROCESSING)

The following is a description (in a clear and plain manner) of what We use Your Personal Data for and the corresponding legal ground(s) we rely on for doing so.

For more detail on what is meant by terms such as **‘Contact Details’** and other categories of Personal Data used in the tables below, please see the section above relating to Personal Data We Collect About You.

**Please note that WHERE WE RELY ON YOUR CONSENT, THIS CAN BE WITHDRAWN AT WILL** (See Special Note on Consent below.)

USERS OF THE SITE AND OF OUR APPS  
---  
PURPOSE OF THE PROCESSING | CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA | LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING  
Set up a record on our systems | 

  * Contact Details
  * Other Communication Data

| 

  * Contractual Necessity
  * Legitimate interest (to ensure we have an accurate record)

To manage our relationship with you | 

  * Contact Details
  * Other Communication Data
  * Transaction and Usage data

| 

  * Contractual Necessity
  * Compliance with the legal obligations

To establish and investigate any suspicious behaviour in order to protect our business from any risk and fraud | 

  * Contact Details

| 

  * Legitimate interest (detection and prevention of fraud)

Subscribing to a newsletter or mailing list | 

  * Contact Details

| 

  * Your consent

Evaluating Your queries and/or requests You send Us to use/receive any of Our services (including Customer Support Services). | 

  * Contact Details

| 

  * Contractual Necessity

Record Keeping of transactions and to generate internal aggregate statistics | 

  * Contact Details
  * Transaction and Usage Data
  * Tracking Data

| 

  * Contractual Necessity
  * Legitimate interest (to ensure accurate record of sales and functionality of our products)

ONGOING CLIENTS OF OUR APPS AND SERVICES  
PURPOSE OF THE PROCESSING | CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA | LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING  
Maintain records on our systems | 

  * Contact Details
  * Other Communication Data

| 

  * Contractual Necessity
  * Legitimate interest (to ensure we have an accurate record)

Continue to manage our relationship with you | 

  * Contact Details
  * Other Communication Data
  * Transaction and Usage Data

| 

  * Contractual Necessity
  * Compliance with the legal obligations

To contact you for customer care purposes | 

  * Contact Details

| 

  * Contractual Necessity
  * Legitimate interests

Your being able to participate in an online survey or poll | 

  * Contact Details

| 

  * Your consent

Comply with legal and regulatory obligations | 

  * Contact Details

| 

  * Legal Obligation

To be able to provide You with (some or all of) Our services – especially those provided via the Site | 

  * Contact Details

| 

  * Contractual Necessity

Subscribing to a newsletter or mailing list | 

  * Contact Details

| 

  * Your consent

To be able to provide You with marketing material that You may have requested from Us or that We may be authorised at law to provide to You | 

  * Marketing Data

| 

  * Your consent (where we need this);  
**OR**
  * Our legitimate interests (where we don’t need Your consent.)

Record Keeping of transactions and internal data analysis | 

  * Contact Details
  * Transaction and Usage Data
  * Tracking Data

| 

  * Contractual Necessity

Should We need to process Your data for a new purpose in the future, which is entirely unrelated to the above, We will inform You of such processing in advance and You may exercise Your applicable rights (as explained below) in relation to such processing.

Finally, do note that without certain Personal Data relating to You, We may not be in the position to provide some or all of the services You expect from Us or even to guarantee the full functionality of Our Site.

## SPECIAL NOTE ON CONSENT

For the avoidance of all doubt, We would like to point out that in those limited cases where We cannot or choose not to rely on another legal ground (for example, Our legitimate interests), We will process Your Personal Data on the basis of Your consent.

In those cases where We process on the basis of Your consent ( **which We will never presume** but which We shall have obtained in a clear and manifest manner from You), **YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO WITHDRAW YOUR CONSENT AT ANY TIME** and this, in the same manner as You shall have provided it to Us.

Should You exercise Your right to withdraw Your consent at any time (by writing to Us at the physical or email address below), We will determine whether at that stage an alternative legal basis exists for processing Your Personal Data (for example, on the basis of a legal obligation to which We are subject) where We would be legally authorised (or even obliged) to process Your Personal Data without needing Your consent and if so, notify You accordingly.

When We ask for such Personal Data, You may always decline, however should You decline to provide Us with necessary data that We require to provide requested services, We may not necessarily be able to provide You with such service (especially if consent is the only legal ground that is available to Us).

Just to clarify, **consent is not the only ground that permits Us to process Your Personal Data.** In the last preceding section above We pointed out the various grounds that We rely on when processing Your Personal Data for specific purposes.

## ACCURACY OF PERSONAL DATA

All reasonable efforts are made to keep any Personal Data We may hold about You up-to-date and as accurate as possible. You can check the information that We hold about You at any time by contacting Us in the manner explained below. If You find any inaccuracies, We will correct them and where required, delete them as necessary. **Please seebelow for a detailed list of Your legal rights in terms of any applicable data protection law.**

## DIRECT MARKETING

**We only send mail, messages, emails and other communications relating to marketing where We are authorised to do so at law**. In most cases We rely on Your consent to do so (especially where We use electronic communications). If, at any time, You no longer wish to receive direct marketing communications from Us please let Us know by contacting Us at the details below or update Your preferences on any of Our Site(s) or Apps (where applicable).

In the case of direct marketing sent by electronic communications (where We are legally authorised to do so) You will be given an easy way of opting out (or unsubscribing) from any such communications.

**Please note that even if You withdraw any consent You may have given Us or if You object to receiving such direct marketing material from Us (in those cases where We do not need Your consent), from time to time We may still need to send You certain important communications from which You cannot opt out.**

## TRANSFERS TO THIRD COUNTRIES

As a general rule, the data We process about You (collected via the Site, any of our Apps or otherwise) will be stored and processed within the European Union (EU)/European Economic Area (EEA) or any other non-EEA country deemed by the European Commission to offer an adequate level of protection (the so-called ‘white-listed’ countries listed here: <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>.)

In some cases, it may be necessary for Us to transfer Your Personal Data to a non-EEA country not considered by the European Commission to offer an adequate level of protection (for example to one or more of Our data processors located there.)

In such cases, apart from all appropriate safeguards that We implement, in any case, to protect Your Personal Data, We have put in place additional adequate measures. For example, We have ensured that the recipient is bound by the EU Standard Contractual Clauses (the EU Model Clauses) designed to protect Your Personal Data as though it were an intra-EEA transfer. You are entitled to obtain a copy of these measures by contacting Us as explained below.

## INTERNET COMMUNICATIONS

You will be aware that data sent via the Internet may be transmitted across international borders even where sender and receiver of information are located in the same country. We cannot be held responsible for anything done or omitted to be done by You or any third party in connection with any Personal Data prior to Our receiving it including but not limited to any transfers of Personal Data from You to Us _via_ a country having a lower level of data protection than that in place in the European Union, and this, by any technological means whatsoever (for example, WhatsApp, Skype, Dropbox, etc.).

**Moreover, We shall accept no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the security of Your data while in transit through the Internet unless Our responsibility results explicitly from a law having effect in Malta.**

## AUTHORISED DISCLOSURES

Without prejudice to anything contained in this Privacy Policy and in the interest of full transparency, We reserve the right to disclose (and otherwise process) any relevant Personal Data relating to You which We may be processing (including in certain cases relevant IP addresses) to authorised third parties in or outside the EU/EEA if such disclosures are allowed under the Data Protection Laws (whether or not You have provided Your consent) including but not limited to:

  1. For the purpose of preventing, detecting or suppressing fraud (for example, if You provide false or deceptive information about Yourself or attempt to pose as someone else, We may disclose any information We may have about You in Our possession so as to assist any type of investigation into Your actions);
  2. in the event of Uniblue Systems Limited **** being involved in a merger, sale, restructure, acquisition, joint venture, assignment, transfer;
  3. to protect and defend Our rights (including the right to property), safety, or those of Our affiliates, of Users of Our Site or even Your own;
  4. to protect against abuse, misuse or unauthorised use of Our Site;
  5. for any purpose that may be necessary for the performance of any agreement You may have entered into with Us (including the request for provision of services by third parties) or in order to take steps at Your request prior to entering into a contract;
  6. to comply with any legal obligations such as may arise by way of response to any Court subpoena or order or similar official request for Personal Data; or
  7. as may otherwise be specifically allowed or required by or under any applicable law (for example, under anti-money laundering legislation.)

## SHARING OF PERSONAL DATA WITH OTHER CATEGORIES OF RECIPIENTS

Relevant data will also be disclosed or shared as appropriate (and in all cases in line with the Data Protection Laws) to/with members and staff of Uniblue Systems Limited, to/with other entities within the Uniblue Systems Limited and/or to/with affiliated entities and/or sub-contractors established within the European Union if pertinent to any of the purposes listed in this Privacy Policy (including to/with Our services providers who facilitate the functionality of the Site and/or any service You may require). Personal information will only be shared by Us to provide the services You request from Us or for any other lawful reason (including authorised disclosures not requiring Your consent.)

Any such authorised disclosures will be done in accordance with the Data Protection laws (for example all Our processors are contractually bound by the requirements in the said Data Protection Laws, including a strict obligation to keep any information they receive confidential and to ensure that their employees/personnel are also bound by similar obligations). The said service providers (Our processors) are also bound by a number of other obligations (in particular, Article 28 of the GDPR.)

**Your Personal Data will never be shared with third parties for their marketing purposes (unless You give Your consent thereto.)**

The third parties who We may disclose to and/or share Your Personal Data with are, at the date of this Privacy Policy, the following:

CATEGORY OF RECIPIENT | PURPOSE OF PROCESSING  
---|---  
Cloud Service Providers | Hosting of data under state-of-the-art security protocols and our exclusive control.  
IT Service Providers | Maintenance and support of our IT systems/Website(s) – with restricted access and under our strict controls.  
Customer Support Software Provider | Provision of a customer support software in order to provide our users with a high level customer support with restricted access and our strict control.  
Marketing and Customer Retention Management Tools | Provision of marketing email communications send outs under our strict control and management.  
Public Authorities | Compliance with legal obligations and only after verifications are made into necessity of disclosure.  
  
## SECURITY MEASURES

The personal information which We may hold (and/or transfer to any affiliates/partners/subcontractors as the case may be) will be held securely in accordance with Our internal security policy and the law.

We use reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of any and/or all Personal Data that We may process relating to You and regularly review and enhance Our technical, physical and managerial procedures so as to ensure that Your Personal Data is protected from:

  * unauthorised access,
  * improper use or disclosure,
  * unauthorised modification,
  * unlawful destruction or accidental loss.

To this end We have implemented security policies, rules and technical and organisational measures to protect the Personal Data that We may have under Our control. All our members, staff and data processors (including specific subcontractors, including cloud service providers established within the European Union), who may have access to and are associated with the processing of Personal Data, are further obliged (under contract) to respect the confidentiality of Our Users’ or clients’ Personal Data as well as other obligations as imposed by the Data Protection Laws.

Despite all the above, We cannot guarantee that a data transmission or a storage system can ever be 100% secure. For more information about Our security measures please contact Us in the manner described below.

Authorised third parties, and external/third-party service providers, with permitted access to Your information (as explained in this Privacy Policy) are specifically required to apply appropriate technical and organisational security measures that may be necessary to safeguard the Personal Data being processed from unauthorised or accidental disclosure, loss or destruction and from any unlawful forms of processing.

As stated above, the said service providers (Our data processors) are also bound by a number of other obligations in line with the Data Protection Laws (particularly, Article 28 of the GDPR.)

## RETENTION PERIODS

**We will retain Your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary** (taking into consideration the purpose for which it was originally obtained). The criteria We use to determine what is ‘necessary’ depends on the particular Personal Data in question and the specific relationship We have with You (including its duration).

Our normal practice is to determine whether there is/are any specific EU and/or Maltese law(s) (for example tax or corporate laws) **permitting** or even **_obliging_** Us to keep certain Personal Data for a certain period of time (in which case We will keep the Personal Data for the maximum period indicated by any such law). For example, any data that can be deemed to be ‘accounting records’ must be kept for ten (10) years.

We would also have to determine whether there are any laws and/or contractual provisions that may be invoked against Us by You and/or third parties and if so, what the prescriptive periods for such actions are (this is usually five (5) years). In the latter case, We will keep any relevant Personal Data that We may need to defend Ourselves against any claim(s), challenge(s) or other such action(s) by You and/or third parties for such time as is necessary.

**Where Your Personal Data is no longer required by Us, We will either securely delete or anonymise the Personal Data in question.**

## PROCESSING FOR RESEARCH AND STATISTICAL REASONS

Research and statistics using User or client information is only carried out so that We may understand Our Users’ and/or clients’ needs, to develop and improve Our services/activities and/or for philanthropic goals representative of Uniblue Systems Limited’s purpose. In any case, We will always ensure to obtain any consent We may legally require from You beforehand. As in all other cases, We will also ensure to implement all appropriate safeguards as may be necessary.

## LINKS TO THIRD-PARTY SOURCES

Links that We may provide to third-party websites are clearly marked and We are not in any way whatsoever responsible for (nor can We be deemed to endorse in any way) the content of such websites (including any applicable privacy policies or data processing operations of any kind). We suggest that You should read the privacy policies of any such third-party websites.

## COOKIES

When You visit Our Site, We collect certain categories of Personal Data automatically through the use of cookies and similar technologies.

For more detailed information including what cookies are and how and why We process such data in this manner (including the difference between essential and non-essential cookies) please read Our detailed but easy-to-read Cookie Policy.

## MINORS

The Site and Our services are not intended to be used by any persons under the age of eighteen (18) and therefore We will never intentionally collect any Personal Data from such persons. If You are under the age of consent, please consult and get Your parent’s or legal guardian’s permission to use the Site and to use Our services.

We shall consider that any Personal Data of persohttp://www.uniblue.com/privacy/ns under the age of eighteen (18) received by Us, shall be sent with the proper authority and that the sender can demonstrate such authority at any time, upon Our request.

## YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE DATA PROTECTION LAWS

Before addressing any request You make with Us, We may first need to verify Your identity. In all cases We will try to act on Your requests as soon as reasonably possible.

As explained in the Retention Periods section above, We may need to keep certain Personal Data for compliance with Our legal retention obligations but also to complete transactions that You requested prior to the change or deletion that You requested.

### RIGHTS

Your various rights at law include:

  * ### Your Right of Access

  * ### Your Right to Rectification

  * ### Your Right to Erasure (The Right to be Forgotten)

  * ### Your Right to Data Restriction

  * ### Your Right to Data Portability

  * ### Your Right to Withdraw Consent (when We rely on consent)

  * ### Your Right to Object to Certain Processing

  * ### Your Right to Lodge a Complaint

### WHAT WE MAY REQUIRE FROM YOU

As one of the security measures We implement, before being in the position to help You exercise Your rights as described above We may need to verify Your identity to ensure that We do not disclose to or share any Personal Data with any unauthorised individuals.

### TIME LIMIT FOR A RESPONSE

We try to reply to all legitimate requests within one month from receiving them. In some particular cases (for example, if the matter is particularly complex or if You send Us multiple requests), it may take Us longer than a month. In such cases, we will notify You accordingly and keep You updated.

## UNIBLUE SYSTEMS LIMITED – COMPANY DETAILS

**Uniblue Systems Limited** , a company registered in **Malta** with company registration number **C 32567** and whose registered office address is at PROGETTA HOUSE, GROUND FLOOR, 62-64, TOWER ROAD, SWATAR, BIRKIRKARA, BKR4012, MALTA is the data controller responsible for processing Your Personal Data that takes place via the Site or in the manner explained above (or in the condensed privacy policy or notice that directed You here).

If You have any questions/comments about privacy or should You wish to exercise any of Your individual rights, please contact Us at [info@uniblue.com](mailto:info@uniblue.com), or by writing to UNIBLUE SYSTEMS LIMITED, PROGETTA HOUSE, GROUND FLOOR, 62-64, TOWER ROAD, SWATAR, BIRKIRKARA, BKR4012, MALTA or by phoning Us using telephone number (+356) 23275000 (during normal office hours.)

## UPDATES

We reserve the right, at Our complete discretion, to change, modify, add and/or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time. If You are an existing client with whom We have a contractual relationship You shall be informed by Us of any changes made to this Privacy Policy (as well as other terms and conditions relevant to the Site). We shall also archive and store previous versions of the Privacy Policy for Your review.

As a User of the Site with which We have no contractual relationship or even a lawful way of tracing, it is in Your interest to regularly check for any updates to this Privacy Policy (which are usually deemed to be effective on the date they are published on the Site), in the event that Our attempts to notify You of such updates do not reach You.

Last Updated on 24th May 2018 | Version 24.05.2018

## INTRODUCTION

This cookie policy (“ **Cookie Policy** ”) relates to the website [http://www.uniblue.com](http://www.uniblue.com/) and/or any sub-website and/or associated domains (and/or sub-domains) of [http://www.uniblue.com](http://www.uniblue.com/) (hereinafter referred to as the “ **Site** ”) owned by **Uniblue Systems Limited**. In this Cookie Policy, “ **We** ”, “ **Us** ”, “ **Our** ”, “ **Ourselves** ” and/or “ **Uniblue** ” shall refer to **Uniblue Systems Limited** ( **C 32567** ) and “ **You** ” and “ **Your** ” and “ **User** ” refer to an identified or identifiable natural person being the user of this Site and/or client of any of Uniblue’s services. Our full details, including contact details, can be read below. For more information about how We process Your Personal Data, please read Our Master Privacy Policy.

## WHAT ARE COOKIES?

Our Site uses a technology called “cookies”. A cookie is an element of data (usually a very small file) that a website can send to Your browser, which may then store it on Your computer or mobile device. These cookies allow Us to correctly operate the Site and/or to provide You with web pages or content that are tailored to You. For example, some cookies remember Your custom preferences. This information can, in some cases, be carried from one visit of our Site (or related site) to the next (for example, to help You avoid having to re-enter certain information when You visit the same page later. Some of these cookies require Your consent (as explained below.)

Some cookies are created for each session when You visit Our Site, while others are persistent and may remain for a number of months or years to facilitate Your access to Our Site.

## WHY WE USE COOKIES

**We absolutely respect Your right to privacy.** We use cookies to ensure the functionality of our Site and to make Your website experience better. You can remove any cookies already stored on Your computer or mobile device (as explained below) but this may prevent You from using parts of this Site or may cause You to see this message, or part thereof, again.

Apart from the cookies We make use of Ourselves, various third-party cookies may also be stored on Your computer or mobile device, including [Google Analytics](https://analytics.google.com/analytics/web/provision/?authuser=0#provision/SignUp/) and [New Relic](https://newrelic.com/). We strongly suggest that You read the cookie policy of any such third-party cookies.

## ESSENTIAL AND NON-ESSENTIAL COOKIES

We divide cookies into two main categories, namely:

  1. ### ESSENTIAL COOKIES

These are strictly necessary to ensure that the Site functions in Your everyday use of it or for Us to provide You with the service(s) You expect from Us. Cookies used for the sole purpose of carrying out or facilitating the transmission of a communication will also be considered as essential cookies. **We do not require Your consent to use such essential cookies but You may still block or delete them (see below.)**

Some examples of **essential cookies** as found in the European Commission’s EU Internet Handbook (see<http://ec.europa.eu/ipg/basics/legal/cookies/index_en.htm>) are as follows:

    * **USER-INPUT** cookies (session-id) such as first‑party cookies to keep track of the User’s input when filling online forms, shopping carts, etc., for the duration of a session or persistent cookies limited to a few hours in some cases;
    * **AUTHENTICATION** cookies, to identify the User once he has logged in, for the duration of a session;
    * **USER-CENTRIC SECURITY** cookies, used to detect authentication abuses, for a limited persistent duration;
    * **MULTIMEDIA CONTENT PLAYER** cookies, used to store technical data to play back video or audio content, for the duration of a session;
    * **LOAD-BALANCING** cookies, for the duration of session;
    * **USER-INTERFACE CUSTOMISATION** cookies such as language or font preferences, for the duration of a session (or slightly longer);
    * **THIRD-PARTY SOCIAL PLUG-IN CONTENT-SHARING** cookies, for logged-in members of a social network.
  2. ### NON-ESSENTIAL COOKIES

These are not required for the essential functioning of the Site, although they may greatly enhance Your experience of using Our Site. For example, non-essential cookies may be used for the following reasons:

    * **PREFERENCES.** These cookies would remember Your custom preferences. For example, this helps You avoid having to re-enter certain information when You visit the same page later;
    * **MARKETING.** Here, the cookies would be used to gather information about Your browsing habits allowing Us to provide You with more relevant information and material that would be of interest to You;
    * **STATISTICS.** These help Us gather information about users on Our Site(s), such as when You first visited the Site and/or how often You access it and at what particular time. These also include cookies that log how You came across the Site, using which search engine or other link.

**WE SHALL ONLY PLACE NON-ESSENTIAL COOKIES ON YOUR COMPUTER OR MOBILE DEVICE IF YOU CONSENT TO THAT SPECIFIC CATEGORY OF COOKIE** being placed by way of a pop-up on relevant areas of our Site the first time you visit it and possibly subsequently (if necessary) and/or by accepting this Cookie Policy (or other similarly effective mechanism). This will not prevent You from deleting or disabling cookies by modifying Your browser settings as explained below.

**YOU MAY WITHDRAW SUCH CONSENT FOR NON-ESSENTIAL COOKIES _AT ANY TIME_ BY THE SAME METHOD IN WHICH YOU GAVE IT TO US.**

## SPECIFIC COOKIES USED ON THIS SITE

The specific cookies we use on our Site are as follows:

Name of Cookie | Purpose of Cookie | First- or Third-Party | Session Cookie or Persistent Cookie | Type (HTTP/Local Storage etc.)  
---|---|---|---|---  
country | Essential | First-party | Persistent | HTTP  
currency | Essential | First-party | Persistent | HTTP  
csrftoken | Essential | First-party | Persistent | HTTP  
JSESSIONID | Non-essential | Third-party | Session | HTTP  
__utma | Non-essential | Third-party | Session | HTTP  
__utmb | Non-essential | Third-party | Session | HTTP  
__utmc | Non-essential | Third-party | Session | HTTP  
__utmt | Non-essential | Third-party | Session | HTTP  
__utmz | Non-essential | Third-party | Session | HTTP  
  
## HOW TO DELETE OR DISABLE COOKIES VIA YOUR BROWSER

Even if We obtain Your consent to use non-essential cookies or if We use essential cookies (where we don’t need your consent), You can still control Your settings in Your browser to delete or disable cookies.

If Your browser is NOT configured, by default, to block all or certain cookies, You may manually configure Your browser to either reject all cookies or control which cookies are set on Your computer or mobile device through the Site. Should You wish to reject all or certain cookies used by Our Site, You may modify Your web browser preferences to do so.

**If You reject ALL cookies (includingEssential Cookies then You might be unable to use some of the features or services available on Our Site and You might also experience a lack of full functionality of the Site.**

Usually, the information on how to change Your options regarding cookies can be obtained by referring to Your operating system’s manual or to the ‘Help’ section of Your web browser, or by contacting Your Internet Service Provider.

You may also find all the necessary information on how to make the necessary configuration settings by visiting the following helpful site:<http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/>

Please read Our Master Privacy Policy which, among other things, explains all Your rights as a data subject.

For more information please feel free to contact us as indicated below.

## http://www.uniblue.com/privacy/COMPANY DETAILS

Uniblue is the data controller responsible for processing of Your personal data that takes place via the Site or in the manner explained above.

If You have any questions/comments about privacy, You should contact Us at [info@uniblue.com](mailto:info@uniblue.com), or by writing to **UNIBLUE SYSTEMS LIMITED** , PROGETTA HOUSE, GROUND FLOOR, 62-64, TOWER ROAD, SWATAR, BIRKIRKARA, BKR4012, MALTA, or by phoning Us using telephone number (+356) 23275000 (during normal office hours.)

## UPDATES

We reserve the right, at Our complete discretion, to change, modify, add and/or remove portions of this Cookie Policy at any time. If You are an existing client with whom We have a contractual relationship You shall be informed by Us of any changes made to this Cookie Policy (as well as other terms and conditions relevant to the Site). We shall also archive and store previous versions of the Cookie Policy for Your review.

As a User of this Site with which We have no contractual relationship or even a lawful way of tracing, it is in Your interest to regularly check for any updates to this Cookie Policy, in the event that Our attempts to notify You of such updates do not reach You.
